Guide to the Seymour Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Watkins - Law Families, 1837-(1893-1925)-1945; Series XIII; 1'10" (5 boxes)
  - Correspondence
    - Thomas Hamer Watkins: from Seymour, Charles, Jr., 1923-1925 (Box 72, Folder 49)
    - Thomas Hamer Watkins: from Seymour, Elizabeth Atwater, 1923-1925, 1944 (Box 72, Folder 50)
    - Thomas Hamer Watkins: from Seymour, Gladys (Watkins), 1893-1904 (Box 72, Folder 51)
    - Thomas Hamer Watkins: from Seymour, Gladys (Watkins), 1905-1925 (Box 73, Folder 52-56)
    - Thomas Hamer Watkins: from Watkins, Charles Law, 1895-1918 (Box 73, Folder 57-60)
    - Thomas Hamer Watkins: from Watkins, Elizabeth (Law), 1901-1907 (Box 73, Folder 61-62)
    - Thomas Hamer Watkins: from [W[underline]?], Dorothy, 1908 (Box 73, Folder 63)
    - [Thomas H. Watkins?]: to Hunt, A. Everett, Jr., 1907 (Box 74, Folder 64)
    - Unidentified from unidentified, undated (Box 74, Folder 65)
  - Writings
    - Of Charles Law Watkins, [1918?] (Box 74, Folder 66)
  - Printed Material
    - Charles Law Watkins: obituary, 1945 (Box 74, Folder 67)
    - Charles Law Watkins: memorial, 1945 (Box 74, Folder 68)
  - Personal and Memorabilia
    - Elizabeth (Law) Watkins: miscellaneous, 1884-1906, undated (Box 74, Folder 69-70)
    - Thomas Hamer Watkins: mortgage
      See: box 107, folder 61
    - Thomas Hamer Watkins: miscellaneous, 1884-1902, undated (Box 74, Folder 71)
- Charles Seymour, Jr., (1918-1975)-[1978]; Series XIV; 5' (12 boxes)
  Charles Seymour, Jr., was born in New Haven, Connecticut, on February 26, 1912, son of Charles and Gladys (Watkins) Seymour. After graduating from the Choate School in 1930, he spent a year at King's College, Cambridge. Upon returning to this country, he attended Yale, receiving his B.A. in 1935 and his Ph.D. in 1938. He followed this up with study at the University of Paris. On May 4, 1940, he married Charlotte Ball, and they had two children: Charlotte Elizabeth (1941) and Charles, III (1944).
  Following a year at Yale as an instructor in the history of art, Charles Seymour, Jr., joined the staff of the newly-formed National Gallery of Art, serving as curator of sculpture from 1939-1942 and as assistant chief curator from 1945-1949. In these capacities, he gave numerous lectures on various facets of art history. Between 1943 and 1945, he served in military intelligence for the War Department. In 1949, he returned to Yale in the position of assistant professor of the history of art and of curator of Renaissance art. He became chairman of his department in 1956 and held this position until 1959. He remained at Yale as professor of history of art for the rest of his career.
  Charles Seymour, Jr., was a prolific writer and lecturer on the subjects of art history, especially sculpture, and education. His books centering on Italian sculpture include Italian Quattrocento Sculpture, Michelangelo's David, The Sculpture of Verocchio, and Jacopo Della Quercia. He also belonged to C.R.I.A.(Committee for the Rescue of Italian Art). He died on April 7, 1977.
  Correspondence is divided into two sub-sections. Correspondence to Charles Seymour, Jr., from individuals is arranged alphabetically by sender. Correspondence to Charles Seymour, Jr., regarding various topics, is arranged chronologically.
  Writings, which comprises the largest portion of the series, is divided by category into six sub-sections:
  1. Diaries
  2. Books
  3. Articles: Published; Unpublished
  4. Lectures
  5. Notes
  6. Writings of others
  Within each sub-section the material is arranged chronologically.
  Education Studies contains the reports of surveys and investigations on the teaching of art in which Charles Seymour, Jr., participated. The reports are arranged chronologically.
  C.R.I.A., which stands for the Committee for the Rescue of Italian Art, contains correspondence and press releases regarding a C.R.I.A. benefit exhibition, requests for loans, and photographs. The material is arranged by category.
  Courses, which contains course outlines, class record books, and other material relating to the courses taught by Charles Seymour, Jr., is arranged. chronologically.
  Printed Material is arranged by type of material.
  Personal and Memorabilia is arranged in rough chronological order.
  - Correspondence
    - Charles Seymour, Jr., from
      - A-Z, 1932-1975 (Box 75, Folder 1-2)
      - Angel, Elizabeth Day (Seymour), 1918 (Box 75, Folder 3)
      - Clement, Jean, 1939 (Box 75, Folder 4)
      - St. John, Margaret, undated (Box 75, Folder 5)
      - Seymour, Charles (1885-1963), 1921-1937 (Box 75, Folder 6-9)
      - Seymour, Charlotte, 1946 (Box 75, Folder 10)
      - Seymour, Elizabeth Atwater, 1943 (Box 75, Folder 11)
      - Seymour, Gladys (Watkins), undated (Box 75, Folder 12)
      - Walker, John, 1939 (Box 75, Folder 13)
      - Childhood and Choate School letters, 1923-1926, undated (Box 75, Folder 14)
    - To Charles Seymour, Jr., regarding
      - Art history course at Foxcroft School, 1946-1947 (Box 75, Folder 15)
      - Publications, 1946-1949 (Box 75, Folder 16)
      - Focillon Society, 1948 (Box 75, Folder 17)
      - Johns Hopkins University course, 1948-1949 (Box 75, Folder 18)
      - Lectures at Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, 1950 (Box 75, Folder 19)
      - Pelican volume: editor's suggestions, 1959-1969 (Box 75, Folder 20)
      - Publications of Charles Seymour (1885-1963), 1963-1975 (Box 75, Folder 21)
      - Baldwin Lectures at Oberlin College, 1963-1964 (Box 75, Folder 22)
      - Gift of silver spoon to Pierson College, 1964 (Box 75, Folder 23)
      - Visiting Mellon Professorship at the University of Pittsburgh, 1964-1965 (Box 75, Folder 24)
      - Teaching appointment at Johns Hopkins University, 1965 (Box 75, Folder 25)
      - Michelangelo's David, 1966-1968 (Box 75, Folder 26)
      - Verocchio, 1968-1970 (Box 75, Folder 27)
      - Michelangelo: The Sistine Ceiling, 1968-1973 (Box 75, Folder 28)
      - Letters of condolence on the death of Elizabeth Atwater Seymour: A-W, 1969 (Box 75, Folder 29-30)
      - Letters of condolence on the death of Elizabeth Atwater Seymour: first names only, 1969 (Box 75, Folder 31)
    - To the family of Charles Seymour, Jr.
      - Charlotte (Ball) Seymour from Seymour, Elizabeth Atwater, 1945 (Box 75, Folder 32)
      - Charlotte Seymour and Charles Seymour, III, from Seymour, Elizabeth Atwater, [1952?] (Box 75, Folder 33)
  - Writings
    - Diaries, 1924, [1958?], 1965 (Box 76, Folder 34-35)
    - Books
      - Masterpieces of Sculpture from the National Gallery of Art, 1949 (Box 76, Folder 36)
      - Italian Quattrocento Sculpture (Penguin): rough draft outline
        See: box 107, folder 62
      - Italian Quattrocento Sculpture: outline and word count (Box 76, Folder 37)
      - Italian Quattrocento Sculpture: introduction and notes (Box 76, Folder 38)
      - Italian Quattrocento Sculpture: chapter 1 with notes (Box 76, Folder 39)
      - Italian Quattrocento Sculpture: chapter 2 (Box 76, Folder 40)
      - Italian Quattrocento Sculpture: chapter 3, 4 outlines (Box 76, Folder 41)
      - Italian Quattrocento Sculpture: chapter 6-9 (Box 76, Folder 42-45)
      - Italian Quattrocento Sculpture: parts of book (Box 76, Folder 46)
      - Italian Quattrocento Sculpture: bibliography (Box 76, Folder 47)
      - Italian Quattrocento Sculpture: credits for photographs, index (Box 76, Folder 48)
        See also: box 107, folder 63
      - Italian Quattrocento Sculpture: captions for illustrations, plates, lists of figures and plates, guides (Box 77, Folder 49)
        See also: box 107, folder 64
      - Italian Quattrocento Sculpture: maps, plates, space allocation (Box 77, Folder 50)
      - Michelangelo's David: typescript, 1967 (Box 77, Folder 51)
      - Michelangelo's David: first proof, 1967 (Box 77, Folder 52)
      - Michelangelo's David: documentation, 1967 (Box 77, Folder 53)
      - The Sculpture of Verocchio: notes, 1971 (Box 77, Folder 53a)
      - The Sculpture of Verocchio: typescript, 1971 (Box 77, Folder 54)
      - The Sculpture of Verocchio: proof, 1971 (Box 77, Folder 55)
      - The Sculpture of Verocchio: "Further Observations on a Project for a Standard by Verocchio and Leonardo," June 1972 (Box 77, Folder 56)
      - Michelangelo, The Sistine Chapel Ceiling, 1972 (Box 77, Folder 57)
        See also: box 107, folder 65
      - Jacopo Della Quercia: introduction-chapter 4, 1973 (Box 78, Folder 58)
      - Jacopo Della Quercia: chapter 5, first draft, 1973 (Box 78, Folder 59)
      - Jacopo Della Quercia: chapter 5-end, 1973 (Box 78, Folder 60)
      - Jacopo Della Quercia: table of contents-chapter 3, 1973 (Box 78, Folder 61)
      - Jacopo Della Quercia: captions for plates
        See: box 107, folder 66
      - Jacopo Della Quercia: versions of Vasari Vita of Jacopo Della Quercia, 1973 (Box 78, Folder 62)
      - Notre Dame of Noyon in the Twelfth Centur y: preface to paperback edition, 1975 (Box 78, Folder 63)
      - Contributions to volume in honor of Millard Meiss: "A note of Early Titian: The Circumcision Panel at Yale", [1978?] (Box 78, Folder 64)
    - Aritcles: published
      - "The Parlement of Foules," Atlantic Monthly, 1929-1930 (Box 78, Folder 65)
      - The Choate Literary Magazine, 1929-1930 (Box 78, Folder 66)
      - Article about King's College, Cambridge, The Choate News
        See: box 107, folder 67
      - Yale Literary Magazine, 1932-1933 (Box 78, Folder 67)
      - The Harkness Hoot, 1933 (Box 79, Folder 68-70)
      - The Elizabethan Club: program, 1933 (Box 79, Folder 71)
      - "La Cathedrale de Noyon", [1938?] (Box 79, Folder 72)
      - "Versailles' Fountains," "A Madonna of Humility and Quercia's Early Style," Gazette Des Beaux-Arts, [1938?] (Box 79, Folder 73)
      - "Houdon's Washington at Mount Vernon", 1947 (Box 79, Folder 74)
      - "Our Tradition in Sculpture," The N.Y. Times, 1948 (Box 79, Folder 75)
      - Articles in the Bulletin of the Associates in Fine Arts at Yale University, 1951-1955 (Box 79, Folder 76)
      - Articles re: Nathan Perkins Seymour house in Hudson, Ohio
      - "Louise Mayer Rabinowitz," Bulletin of the Associates in Fine Arts at Yale University, 1957 (Box 79, Folder 77)
      - "The Younger Masters of the First Campaign of the Porta della Mandorla, 1391-1397" [typescript], 1958 (Box 79, Folder 78)
      - "The Rabinowitz Collection," Yale Alumni Magazine, 1960 (Box 79, Folder 79)
      - "Early Republican Masterpiece," Arts in Virginia, 1962 (Box 79, Folder 80)
      - "Technique and Expression in Early Italian Painting," Art International, [1962?) (Box 79, Folder 81)
      - "Vermeer and Cam". original contemplation
        See: box 107, folder 69
      - "A Newly Acquired Italian Mater Domini for Williams College," Art Journal, 1966 (Box 79, Folder 82)
      - "Thirteenth Century Art and the Development of the Gothic Caryatid", undated (Box 79, Folder 83)
      - "An Attribution to Riccio and Other Recent Acquisitions in Bronze and Brass", undated (Box 79, Folder 84)
      - "Curator's Report: Antonia Rosselino, Madonna and Child", undated (Box 79, Folder 85)
      - "Fatto Di Sua Mano"
        See: box 107, folder 70
      - Frick Catalogue: introduction
        See: box 107, folder 71
      - Book reviews
        See: box 107, folder 72
      - Letters to the Editor, New Haven Register, 1967-1969 (Box 79, Folder 86)
    - Articles: unpublished
      - Choate School papers, 1924-1930 (Box 79, Folder 87)
      - Yale College papers, poem, 1932-1935 (Box 79, Folder 88)
      - "Democritus as Melancholy" [student paper?], [1930's?]
      - "Ver Perpetuum": McLaughlin Prize essay, [1931?] (Box 79, Folder 89)
      - Focillon course: "Identification of Three Ivories at the Metropolitan Museum"
        See: box 108, folder 74
      - "The Arch of Alfonso of Aragon in Naples" [undergraduate paper?], undated (Box 79, Folder 90)
      - "Noyon and the Gothic Harmonic Facade", undated (Box 79, Folder 91)
      - "A Byzantine Panel in the Jarves Collection and El Greco's Style" (Box 79, Folder 92)
      - "Henri Focillon": draft of article for Dictionary of American Biography, [1969?] (Box 79, Folder 93)
    - Lectures
      - Christmas address: American University, 1941 (Box 79, Folder 95)
      - For the Archeological Society of Washington, 1941 (Box 79, Folder 96)
      - "Verocchio and the Medici," National Gallery of Art Lectures, 1942 (Box 79, Folder 97)
      - "National Gallery of Art," Baltimore Educational Society lecture, 1942 (Box 79, Folder 98)
      - "Relations between Painting and Sculpture," Phillips Memorial Gallery lecture, 1942 (Box 79, Folder 99)
      - "Inauguration of Georg Erlich's Sculpture Group: Singing Girls," Columbus Gallery of Fine Art, 1942 (Box 80, Folder 100)
      - National Gallery of Art lectures: "Sculpture in the National Gallery of Art", 1942 (Box 80, Folder 101)
      - National Gallery of Art lectures: "Modern Sculpture and Its Relation to Painting", [1942?] (Box 80, Folder 102)
      - National Gallery of Art lectures: "A Portrait of Lorenzo the Magnificient", 1946 (Box 80, Folder 103)
      - National Gallery of Art lectures: "Chartres Cathedral", 1946 (Box 80, Folder 104)
      - "Art in the Washington Community," Art Workshop panel discussion, 1946 (Box 80, Folder 105)
      - "Houdon in America", 1947 (Box 80, Folder 106)
      - "Jean-Baptiste Carpeaux," National Gallery of Art, 1947 (Box 80, Folder 107)
      - "The Negro as Depicted in American Art," Howard University, 1948 (Box 80, Folder 108)
      - "Christmas Art: The Nativity by Petrus Christus", 1948 (Box 80, Folder 109)
      - "The Tribute Money," chapel talk, [1948?] (Box 80, Folder 110)
      - "The Stone Wonders of Naumberg", 1949 (Box 80, Folder 111)
      - "Michelangelo and the David Theme," National Gallery of Art, 1949 (Box 80, Folder 112)
      - "Masterpieces of Sculpture in the National Gallery of Art," Maryland Institute, 1949 (Box 80, Folder 113)
      - "Tradition and Experiment in Modern Sculpture", 1949 (Box 80, Folder 114)
      - Maillol lecture, National Gallery of Art, 1949 (Box 80, Folder 115)
      - Siena lecture
        See: box 108, folder 75
      - "Landscape Painting: A Study of Modes," Norfolk, [1950?] (Box 80, Folder 116)
      - "French 18th Century Sculpture in the Kress Collection," National Gallery of Art tenth anniversary, 1951 (Box 80, Folder 117)
      - "The Challenge of the Past," Western Reserve University, 1951 (Box 80, Folder 118)
      - "The Theater d'Eau at Versailles and Its Sculpture," National Gallery of Art, [1951?] (Box 80, Folder 119)
      - "Art in the Round: Sculpture," Baltimore Museum, 1954 (Box 80, Folder 120)
      - College Art Association meeting in Philadelphia on the conservation of old paintings, 1954 (Box 80, Folder 121)
      - Baroque lecture, National Gallery of Art, [1955?] (Box 80, Folder 122)
      - Gallery talk at Boulder, Colorado, 1958 (Box 80, Folder 123)
      - Yale Alumni Board talk, 1958 (Box 80, Folder 124)
      - "The Object of Art and Historical Investigation", 1959 (Box 80, Folder 125)
      - "The Poetic Image," Boulder, Colorado, 1961 (Box 80, Folder 126)
      - "The Della Robbias and Painting", 1962 (Box 80, Folder 127)
      - "The Image of Man and the World," Brown University, 1962 (Box 80, Folder 128)
      - "Italian Painting: Three Modes of Vision", 1962 (Box 80, Folder 129)
      - "Remarks on Damage and Preservation," "Invention and Revival in Nicolo Pisan's Heroic Style," International History of Art Congress, 1962 (Box 81, Folder 130)
      - "Technique and Expression in Early Italian Painting," Walters Gallery, Baltimore, 1962 (Box 81, Folder 131)
      - Lectures on James Jackson, Frick Collection, Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, 1963 (Box 81, Folder 132)
      - "The Young Man Della Robbia," Oberlin, 1968 (Box 81, Folder 133)
      - "The International Style in Relation to Early Renaissance Sculpture," Columbia, 1963 (Box 81, Folder 134)
      - "The Search for Identity in Michelangelo's Sculpture," Mellon Lecture, 1965 (Box 81, Folder 136)
      - "Michelangelo's Search for Identity," Princeton, [1965?] (Box 81, Folder 137)
      - "Romantic Aspects of Florentine Renaissance Sculpture," National Gallery of Art, 1966 (Box 81, Folder 138)
      - "The Renaissance Image of Man in the World: Sculpture in the Age of Donatello" Baldwin Lectures, Oberlin, 1964 (Box 81, Folder 135)
      - "Some Aspects of Donatello's Methods of Figure and Space," Donatello Congress, 1966 (Box 81, Folder 139)
      - Address: Laycock School, 1967 (Box 81, Folder 140)
      - "Our Florentine Heritage," Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1969 (Box 81, Folder 141)
      - "Michelangelo's David," Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1969 (Box 81, Folder 142)
      - "Sketch of Thomas Day Seymour," Old Gentlemen's Club, 1969 (Box 81, Folder 143)
        See also: box 113, folder 108
      - "Wood-Panel Paintings," College Art Association meeting, 1969 (Box 81, Folder 144)
      - "Houdon in America," Municipal Arts Society of Baltimore, 1969 (Box 81, Folder 145)
      - "Art and Education," Boston College, 1969 (Box 81, Folder 146)
      - "Houdon: Sculpture of the Libertarian Tradition," Associates of the Rare Books Room, Colorado University, 1969 (Box 81, Folder 147)
      - "The Role of Special Exhibitions and Problems of Conservation," College Art Association meeting, 1970 (Box 81, Folder 148)
      - "The Painter and the Camera's Eye," Chautauqua, Boulder, 1970 (Box 81, Folder 149)
      - To the Yale Class of 1908, 1970 (Box 81, Folder 150)
      - "Venice 1971," Pierson College fellows (Box 81, Folder 151)
      - "Introduction to Films on Venice and Rome," Yale Art Gallery Associates, 1971 (Box 81, Folder 152)
      - "James Jackson Jarves and his Collection of Primitives", 1972 (Box 81, Folder 153)
      - "Reflections on Filarete's Use of Antique Visual Sources", 1972 (Box 82, Folder 154)
      - "Landscapes of Provence by Cezanne and Van Gogh", 1972-1973 (Box 82, Folder 155)
      - "Jacopo Della Quercia", 1973, 1974 (Box 82, Folder 156)
      - "Quattrocento Sculpture for the Medici", 1974 (Box 82, Folder 157)
      - "Venice: Yesterday, Today (And Tomorrow?)," Yale Faculty Club, 1974 (Box 82, Folder 158)
      - "Mirrors and Painting," Old Gentlemen's Club, 1974 (Box 82, Folder 159)
      - "Medici Patronage of Sculpture," National Gallery of Art, [1974?] (Box 82, Folder 160)
      - "Medici Sculpture in the National Gallery of Art," National Gallery of Art, 1975 (Box 82, Folder 161)
      - "Gothic or Revival? Some Aspects of Definition of Style in Italian Sculpture 1395-1620," Smith College, 1975 (Box 82, Folder 162)
      - "The Athenian Acropolis before Pericles", 1976 (Box 82, Folder 163)
      - "Alice and Art", undated (Box 82, Folder 164)
      - "Twain, Hawthorne, and Florence," Pierson College, undated (Box 82, Folder 165)
      - "Homo Magnus et Albus: The Quattrocento Background for Michelangelo's David of 1501-1504", undated (Box 82, Folder 166)
      - Remarks on the "course" system, undated (Box 82, Folder 167)
      - "Italian Renaissance of the Widener Collection", undated (Box 82, Folder 168)
      - "Comments on the President's Report," Education Policy Committee, undated (Box 82, Folder 169)
      - "Romantic Aspects of Florentine Renaissance Sculpture", undated (Box 82, Folder 170)
      - "Space in Sculpture," Watkins Gallery, undated (Box 82, Folder 171)
      - "The Rome of Julius II," University of Missouri, undated (Box 82, Folder 172)
      - Portraiture in the 17th Century (Sculpture), 1941 (Box 79, Folder 94)
    - notes
      - Course notes taken at the Ecole des chartes, Paris (Box 82, Folder 173-174)
      - Student notebooks, Focillon restricted course, Paris, 1936-1937 (Box 83, Folder 175)
      - notes for article: "Ghiberti and the Antigone," Renaissance News, 1937 (Box 83, Folder 176)
      - notes and drawings of European classical, Gothic, Romanesque and Byzantine architecture, [1930's?] (Box 83, Folder 177)
      - Davies list of 15th century tombs in Rome, undated (Box 83, Folder 178)
      - Donatello, notes on, undated (Box 83, Folder 179)
      - Florence Cathedral, undated (Box 83, Folder 180)
      - 15th century Lombard style, undated (Box 83, Folder 181)
      - "Renaissance Problems", undated (Box 83, Folder 182)
      - Renaissance theaters: diagrams, information, undated (Box 83, Folder 183)
      - Roman Renaissance sculpture, undated (Box 83, Folder 184)
      - Serra study: outline, undated (Box 83, Folder 185)
      - Sicilian school, undated (Box 83, Folder 186)
      - San Michelle, Pistoia, Venice, undated (Box 83, Folder 187)
    - By Others
      - Student Papers
        - Colin T. Eisler, "Antonello Da Messina", 1951 (Box 83, Folder 188)
        - [no name], "The Rimini Master", 1956 (Box 83, Folder 189)
        - Peter W. Milton, "Three Panels from the Cantoria by Luca Della Robbia", 1961 (Box 83, Folder 190)
        - John Cameron, "Les Chapiteaus du XIe Siecle de la Cathedrale du Mans", 1966 (Box 83, Folder 191)
        - Jacqueline Falkenheim, "Michelangelo's Three Statues", 1967 (Box 83, Folder 192)
        - D.J. Johnson, "Dialogues in the Door of the Apostles", 1967 (Box 83, Folder 193)
        - Gloria Keach, "Luca Signorelli's Frescoes for the S. Brizio Chapel", 1969 (Box 83, Folder 194)
        - Otto Nauman, "The Church of San Francesco in Assisi", 1972 (Box 83, Folder 195)
        - Dorsey McConnell, "Fragments", 1974 (Box 83, Folder 196)
        - Jane Bayard, "Satyr's Head-Drawing by Michelangelo in the Louvre", 1975 (Box 83, Folder 197)
        - Yasuko Betchaka, "Michelangelo's Sistine Chapel Ceiling Painting", 1975 (Box 83, Folder 198)
        - David H. Solkin, "Henry Fuseli Encounters Michelangelo", 1975 (Box 83, Folder 199)
        - Paul Cardile, "Fra Angelico and His Workshop", undated (Box 83, Folder 200)
        - John Cutler, "Leonardo Da Vinci as a Sculptor" [with photographs], undated (Box 83, Folder 201)
        - Fred Brown, "Elements of Neo-platonism in Michelangelo's Sistine Ceiling", undated (Box 83, Folder 202)
        - Virginia Raquin, "The Reliefs of the Courtyard of the Casa Scala, Florence", undated (Box 83, Folder 203)
        - J.P., "Gentile Da Fabriano", undated (Box 83, Folder 204)
        - Paul Watson, "Allegories of Courtly Love in Early Florentine Cassoni and Deschi", undated (Box 83, Folder 205)
      - Miscellaneous
        - Typescript of Henri Focillon Lecture: "L'Emeute", undated (Box 83, Folder 206)
        - Recommendations to Charles Seymour, Jr., from J. Spenser, undated (Box 83, Folder 207)
  - Education Studies
    - Harvard University report on art department: course data, [1947-1952?] (Box 84, Folder 208)
    - Princeton University report on art department: course data, [ca 1950] (Box 84, Folder 209)
    - Yale University report on art department: course data, 1951 (Box 84, Folder 210)
    - Lawrenceville School report on art department: course data, 1952 (Box 84, Folder 211)
    - Phillips Academy report on art department: course data, 1952 (Box 84, Folder 212)
    - Summary: "Fine Arts Survey", [ca 1952] (Box 84, Folder 213)
    - "A Committee Report on the Integration of School and College", 1952 (Box 84, Folder 214)
    - Speech to alumni: "Ford Report: General Education in School and College", 1953 (Box 84, Folder 215)
  - C.R.I.A. (Committee for the Rescue of Italian Art)
    - C.R.I.A. correspondence, 1967 (Box 85, Folder 216)
    - C.R.I.A. exhibition: list of works, 1967 (Box 85, Folder 217)
    - C.R.I.A. exhibition: catalogue introduction and proof cheets
      See: box 108, folder 76
    - C.R.I.A. talk, 1967 (Box 85, Folder 218)
    - Press releases, publicity picture, miscellaneous information, 1967 (Box 85, Folder 219)
    - The state of the restoration (outline), 1967 (Box 85, Folder 220)
  - Courses